# LAUREN DUNN

# DIGITAL CONTENT PRODUCER AT FACING HISTORY AND OURSELVES

# I WORK ON TOOLS FOR EDUCATORS

I am the digital lead on Facing History's **Current Events project** which provides teaching materials and strategies to help educators connect current events to their curriculum. The project has seen high levels of engagement as measured by:

- Over 2,000 new subscribers to Current Events email list within the first 6 months of the project.
- Email open rates averaging 38%, click-through rates averaging 5%.
- Average time on page for our current events content is > 5 min, ranging between
   5 and 10+ minutes.

# MY RESPONSIBILITIES ON THE CURRENT EVENTS PROJECT INCLUDE

- Editing and building biweekly content in Drupal; provide recommendations to optimize content for the web.
- Collaborating with Marketing and Program teams on monitoring breaking news stories and tracking content production.
- Regularly analyzing content performance to inform future iterations of current events teaching resources.
- Organized a 2018 survey of over 300 educators on how they teach about current events in their classrooms during discovery phase of the project; used results to inform content strategy and information architecture for new content types (Teaching Ideas and Explainers) and overarching Current Events page.

# SINCE JOINING FACING HISTORY IN 2017, I HAVE ALSO WORKED ON:

- Building new educator resource and marketing content in Drupal and Hubspot.
- Providing recommendations for rebuilding and managing existing content.
- Creating content maps, wireframes, and user-facing imagery and copy as needed.
- Collaborating across departments to discuss user experience and objectives for new products and deliverables.
- Pulling Google Analytics metrics and compiling reports and narratives for stakeholders.



# ABOUT ME

I am experienced in collaborating with technical and non-technical colleagues to create digital products that meet the needs of a wide range of audiences. I believe effective design should solve problems, be iterative, and be informed by data. I am passionate about creating accessibile and inclusive products.

# CONTACT

laurenelizabeth.dunn@gmail.com 203.804.9229

# PORTFOLIO

ledunn.github.io

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, jQuery Javascript Version Control (Git) Drupal Google Analytics

### VISUAL DESIGN

Wireframes and Mockups

(Balsamiq, Sketch)

**Graphic Design** 

(web and print)

# LAUREN DUNN

# PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

### Freelance Web Designer, 2015- Present

- Consult with small business owners and professional artists to outline customized website goals and functionality. See portfolio examples at ledunn.github.io.
- Change design elements through multiple iterations based on client feedback.
- Develop site layout and concept from sketches and mockups to completed live sites. I work on client sites that are hand-coded as well as run through CMS such as Squarespace.
- Train clients to maintain own websites after launch

### Instructor, Brookline Adult and Continuing Education, 2017-2018

- Taught 4-week and 8-week courses to adult students; provided feedback on their design work and presented on best practices for graphic and web design.
- Course topics included: Introduction to Graphic Design, Introduction to Adobe Illustrator, Introduction to Javascript, and HTML5 and CSS3: Building the Modern Web.

# BEFORE MAKING A CAREER CHANGE, I GAINED EXPERIENCE AS:

### Book Scanning Associate, Internet Archive, 2012-2014

- Digitized images from books and documents and edited digital files for public viewing online.
- Asserted metadata for digitized media to enable SEO.

# Bartender, Legal Sea Foods, 2011-2016

- Appointed to progressively responsible positions over course of employment (promoted to Lead Server and Bartender).
- Selected to attend two 6-week professional development seminars on wine and spirits.
- Responsible for training new employees through teaching classes and on-the-job training shifts.

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

## Mentor, Mentor 2.0 Program (Big Brothers Big Sisters Massachusetts Bay), 2017-Present

I am paired 1-1 with a high school student for the course of her high school career. Mentor 2.0 is focused on providing college prep support and life skills training to low-income and first-generation high school students with the goal of helping them excel in high school, enter and graduate college, and succeed in their adult life.

### CONTACT

laurenelizabeth.dunn@gmail.com 203.804.9229

#### **PORTFOLIO**

ledunn.github.io

#### **EDUCATION**

# **B.A., Cultural Anthropology**Bard College

# Certificate (anticipated 2020) Graphic Design School of the Museum of Fine

School of the Museum of Fine Arts at Tufts University

### AWARDS

Selected as a Trustee Leader Scholar through Bard College's **TLS Civic Engagement Program**.

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

### **Adobe Creative Suite**

(Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop)

# **Project Management Tools**

Jira, Basecamp, Slack

# Microsoft Office Suite

(Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

# **Google Suite**

(Docs, Sheets, Forms, Slides, Sites)